Zachary Seymour

My experiences at a top university and early entry into a start-up company have encouraged my creative initiative to convert abstract problems into logical solutions. I thrive with the opportunity to manage projects with seniors and juniors working with me for a range of views and abilities to aid my own.

London, UK +44 7399 475244 zacseymour968@googlemail.com LinkedIn GitHub

EXPERIENCE

Blue Copal, City of London, UK — Lead Developer

April 2024 - PRESENT

 Promoted as recognition of the additional responsibilities I had already taken on and the capacity of work I both produced and project-managed.

Blue Copal, City of London, UK — Software Developer

August 2022 - April 2024

- I was hired full-time to work as a full-stack developer within a
 team to continue and create multiple applications for both
 regular auction trading and fast-paced market trading for the GB
 energy market (later expanding to European markets). This
 involved using the **Phoenix Web Framework** to provide UX and
 data for traders on top of an **Elixir** backend, which used an **Ecto**DB connection.
- This evolved into contributing towards the CI/CD part of the development to allow agile testing and release of new features, using skills listed on the right.
- During the recruitment phase, I was solely responsible for producing an Elixir coding challenge for candidates, assessing responses, and extending the task as part of a live-coding interview.
- When the junior developers joined, I continued to be involved with onboarding and then gained the responsibility of project management. I took multiple projects from the drawing board to release, as well as numerous features and bug fixes, which involved creating the solution and dividing tasks into agile sections for multiple developers (both junior and senior to me) to undertake.
- Projects:
 - WattFlow auction management and volume recycling
 - BlueBell fast-paced energy and cross-market trading
 - o ImbalSystem cross-app imbalance volume monitoring
 - FormulaBuilder string to Elixir function compiler
 - UserAccounts extension to Phoenix user system

SKILLS

Project Management - Agile & Scrum, Jira

CI/CD - Azure Pipelines, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, ArgoCD

Documentation - Slab

Collaboration-Slack/MS Teams

Recruitment – coding challenges and interviews

LANGUAGES

Elixir Python Java JavaScript Go Haskell

(CSS+HTML)

FRAMEWORKS

Phoenix Django

Blue Copal, City of London, UK— Software Developer Intern

April 2021 - September 2021

- During a 5 month industrial placement as part of my MEng Computing, I worked on the first draft of GB Market Manager (later called WattFlow), where I was given a loose specification of the application that the traders wanted to use. I had to make architecture decisions which would stay in place for the entire life span of the application, which after continuing during full-time employment became the most stable and successful application of the array created during my time at Blue Copal.

 Towards the end of my internship, the company looked to hire new developers for another part of the development, and I introduced the concept of a sedimental page to the company and
- introduced the concept of a coding challenge to the company and helped design and test it before putting it to candidates.

EDUCATION

Imperial College London, London, UK— MEnq Computing

I received a 2:1 for my integrated master's degree. Gained experience in multiple languages across many modules, and was introduced to hybrid working due to the lockdown from mid-second year. I improved my ability to collaborate effectively and developed my communication skills and confidence to present to an audience.

Key projects:

- DeFi Liquidation Bot CPP Group Project Award 20/21
 - Used **Go** to create a bot to crawl three lending protocols on the Ethereum blockchain and find accounts that could be liquidated. It used a bespoke algorithm to calculate whether it would be profitable in the current market.
 - Created a visualiser tool for historical liquidation data from four lending protocols, using the **Django** framework in Python 3.
- WACC
 - Wrote a compiler from scratch for the "WACC" language given a language specification in Backus-Naur Form.
 - I took a lead role in this project, making major design decisions. My first introduction to the importance of backwards compatibility for introducing new features.
 - We used the **ANTLR4** language for our parser generator and wrote our compiler in Java.

PintOS

- Wrote an operating system written in **C** that needed a preemptive, priority scheduler implemented, as well as virtual memory and the ability for user programs to run.
- Required to write malleable code that could be changed with each new lecture teaching us new techniques and problems to consider as part of the solution.

Woking College, Surrey, UK— A-Levels

2016 - 2018

A* - Maths, A - Further Maths, Physics, Computer Science

Introduced to the Java language.

Woking High School, Surrey, UK— GCSEs

2011 - 2016

A^ - Further Maths, A* - Maths, Physics, Biology, History, A - Computing, Chemistry, English Language, English Literature, Latin, Statistics

Introduced to Python 2.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Avala Catering, Surrey, UK— Waiter and Kitchen Porter

2018 - 2019

- Provided services as a waiter at both large and small events, supervised the bar's running on many occasions and supported the chefs in the kitchen.
- Working for Avala improved my ability to work in a team in high-pressure environments and demonstrate customer and client interactions.

HC-One, Surrey, UK — Waiter and Kitchen Porter

2017 - 2018

- I waited on the elderly in a retirement village, serving lunches at weekends and dinners on special events, and solely provided a bar service at several events.
- I have developed communication skills with a range of people, including those less able due to conditions such as dementia.

HOBBIES

I have always enjoyed playing sports, with football being my primary sport for 10 years of my childhood/teenage years, where I captained my team to multiple division victories. Since finishing university I have also began to socially start tennis, badminton, golf, and indoor bouldering.

REFERENCES

References available on request.